<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title></title>
  <link href="http://benjreinhart.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://benjreinhart.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2011-11-14T21:49:13-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://benjreinhart.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Ben Reinhart</name>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Law Schools</title>
    <link href="http://benjreinhart.github.com/blog/2011/11/14/law-schools/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-14T20:14:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://benjreinhart.github.com/blog/2011/11/14/law-schools</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many students &amp;#8220;simply cannot earn enough income after graduation to support the debt they incur,&amp;#8221; wrote Richard Matasar,
dean of New York Law School, in 2005, concluding that, &amp;#8220;We may be reaching the end of a golden era for law schools.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above was taken from &lt;a href=&quot;http://online.wsj.com/article/SB119040786780835602.html#articleTabs%3Darticle&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; which
was written in 2007. The quote from even longer ago, 2005. Since then, the economy tanked, schools have gotten more
expensive, and even so, more students are going to law school year after year. Why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;re right, I don&amp;#8217;t really know what I&amp;#8217;m talking about. After all, I don&amp;#8217;t know a damn thing about law, political science,
or the like. But maybe &lt;a href=&quot;http://eagleionline.com/2010/10/15/open-letter-to-interim-dean-brown/&quot;&gt;this guy&lt;/a&gt; knows a thing or two
about the real issues that face a law school student. In it, he explains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;[students] are discouraged, scared, and in many cases, feeling rather hopeless about our chances of ever getting to practice law.
[&amp;#8230;] many of us are in an enormous amount of debt from our legal studies. [&amp;#8230; I am] resentful at the thought that I was convinced
to go to law school by empty promises of a fulfilling and remunerative career.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right. But that&amp;#8217;s just one person&amp;#8217;s opinion, not 100% of the people are going to be happy with their decision. Well, what about
the numerous amount of current students, current lawyers and others actively speaking out against law school on a blog
called &lt;a href=&quot;http://insidethelawschoolscam.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Inside the Law School Scam&lt;/a&gt;? One of these
&lt;a href=&quot;http://insidethelawschoolscam.blogspot.com/2011/11/they-write-letters.html&quot;&gt;letters&lt;/a&gt; is from a U of M Law grad,
who attended law school with his wife, explains they are $340,000 in debt, $170,000 each. Despite having a job himself, he still
warns of his many friends who cannot find adequate jobs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of our law school friends that were laid off eventually found new jobs.  But it took some of them more than a year to find
anything. In addition, many of them are now working for a fraction of their previous salaries in non-legal jobs-which makes
it unlikely that they will ever be able to pay off their loans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bummer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite these very real issues, law schools continue to
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/articles/business/moneybox/2010/10/a_case_of_supply_v_demand.html&quot;&gt;manufacture more lawyers&lt;/a&gt; when there just isn&amp;#8217;t
the need for them. Disappointing to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are even movements by &lt;a href=&quot;http://lawschoolscam.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;lawyers themselves to bring awareness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s just amazing to me that so many people still want to go to law school. There is nothing wrong with studying law.
I can understand the appeal it has for many people. What I can&amp;#8217;t understand is why someone considering law school can&amp;#8217;t
take the time to understand the current state of affairs in an industry their looking to join. If they still feel
really strongly about it&amp;#150;that it&amp;#8217;s what they love to do&amp;#150;then so be it. But you better have one hell of a
plan of how you&amp;#8217;re going to separate yourself from the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Failure and Education</title>
    <link href="http://benjreinhart.github.com/blog/2011/10/23/failure-and-education/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-23T00:16:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://benjreinhart.github.com/blog/2011/10/23/failure-and-education</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On the topic of an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2011/10/23/opinion/sunday/will-dropouts-save-america.html&quot;&gt;article in the NY Times by Michael Ellsberg&lt;/a&gt;,
I&amp;#8217;d like to take note of a couple things. I&amp;#8217;m not as radical as Michael Ellsberg is, but one thing that
really, really hit home, and I think is really scary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, entrepreneurs must embrace failure. I spent the last two years interviewing college dropouts
who went on to become millionaires and billionaires. All spoke passionately about the importance of their
business failures in leading them to success. &lt;strong&gt;Our education system encourages students to play it safe
and retreat at the first sign of failure&lt;/strong&gt; (assuming that any failure will look bad on their college
applications and résumés).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve found this to be all too accurate in my experience, and I honestly think it&amp;#8217;s something
that could easily hinder any motivation and courage I may have to take a leap of faith and
start a company. My whole life in school, and not even just school, but society as a whole,
seems to always encourage the safe route, and for the masses, &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; rightfully so. But for
those ambitious enough, this negativity is devastating. My whole life I feel as though I&amp;#8217;ve
been passively encouraged to strive for safety, after all, many seem to correlate that with success because
being safe usually means being steady, and being steady usually means no failure, and if you haven&amp;#8217;t
failed, you must be successful, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will openly admit I am &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/13sentences.html&quot;&gt;terrified of failure (#11)&lt;/a&gt;
but everything I seem to read from those successful entrepreneurs is that &lt;strong&gt;they embraced failure
as a step towards success&lt;/strong&gt; (most of them having failed at least once to get where they are now).
I am not nearly as welcoming to failure as I should be, and fear has the potential to prevent people from
taking risks. To me, that&amp;#8217;s a very scary thought. Not just for me personally, but the thousands of others out
there who&amp;#8217;s inspiration, creativity and motivation to make something better may be drowned by the
subconscious plea of society to play it safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If start ups are the best way to &lt;a href=&quot;http://me.lt/363Ag&quot;&gt;create jobs&lt;/a&gt; and innovation, make a difference,
and move society forward, then why does it (at times) feel like taboo to take these risks? Why is
failure not more often recognized as a sign of learning and improving when it is likely the most
important experience a currently successful entrepreneur pays attribution to? Why can&amp;#8217;t society be
more open about failure, and teach that &lt;strong&gt;an appropriate amount of failure is typically healthy to one&amp;#8217;s
education&lt;/strong&gt;? If more people were comfortable with failure, I honestly feel as though taking risks would
be a more honorable trait and that innovation and entrepreneurism would thrive, which is clearly a
positive remedy for the economy and society as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School seems to shelter students by throwing them into a community of people, typically the same age, who
have yet to experience the real world. They like to use the word &amp;#8220;prepare&amp;#8221; and explain that they are
&amp;#8220;preparing students for life.&amp;#8221; Honestly, not as much as you&amp;#8217;d like to think. All they seem to be doing
is further sheltering me from the realities of the real world, the ups and downs, and skewed versions
of the meanings of success and failure. &amp;lt;/rant&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plenty of times, the argument seems to come back to &amp;#8220;Well, school provides a nice, well-rounded education.&amp;#8221;
If what you mean by that is that students find creative ways to limit the work load and skip their non-core classes,
then maybe so. I have two non-core classes left, not including the two non-core classes I am taking right now. Do you
think I strive to learn anything in those classes? The honest truth is that I find the easiest class that fulfills
that requirement, and pass it, leaving little trace that I took that class. This sounds terrible but it&amp;#8217;s only a
matter of prioritizing what&amp;#8217;s important to me. My religion class that I have to take, not important. At least in
comparison to learning the skills that actually matter for my career, which is time consuming enough. Simply put,
although you&amp;#8217;d like to think those liberal studies classes are paying off, the honest truth is that most students don&amp;#8217;t
care &amp;#150; they want as minimal work as possible and often don&amp;#8217;t take them seriously enough to benefit from them,
whether you like it or not, that&amp;#8217;s how it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, the amount of work and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/hubs.html&quot;&gt;socializing that&amp;#8217;s required to get ahead&lt;/a&gt;
in the start up world provides a surprising amount of well-rounded education. Founders can&amp;#8217;t possibly be specialized
in research, product development, sales, marketing,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.thestartuptoolkit.com/2011/10/its-the-ceos-job-to-email-the-first-1000-signups/&quot;&gt;customer service&lt;/a&gt;,
operations, accounting, finance, management and HR, yet early on it is mostly the founders that perform
all these on a regular basis if they want to see their company survive (can you say learning experience?).
Not to mention everything else that is read between the lines from such an experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a final note, I&amp;#8217;d like to address the debates occurring in the education space, school vs. unschool. Why can&amp;#8217;t
institutions that are so rigorously tied up in defending themselves and the education they provide instead realize
that there is plenty to learn from the ambitious drop outs, the unschooling, the self-learning and autodidacts&amp;#8230;
then take this knowledge and use it to shape their programs to accommodate the super ambitious and reintroduce the
idea of aspiration into their student bodies?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do not fear mistakes. You will know failure. Continue to reach out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#150;&lt;strong&gt;Benjamin Franklin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>My Experience at Groupon So Far</title>
    <link href="http://benjreinhart.github.com/blog/2011/07/30/my-experience-at-groupon-so-far/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-30T01:08:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://benjreinhart.github.com/blog/2011/07/30/my-experience-at-groupon-so-far</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today marks the end of my third week working at Groupon as an intern/apprentice. The first week I was with the engineering
support team, getting a feel for the application, writing my first tiny bits of code and seeing how support tickets were handled.
The second week I worked on the front end, getting a feel for that side of the application and this past week I have spent working with
Groupon touch, the mobile version of the Groupon website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far Groupon has been absolutely awesome, I love it there! Having a fun work environment makes all the difference when it comes
to being motivated to work hard. Appreciating your employers and what they do for you makes you want to contribute back so much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working on the mobile version of Groupon has exposed me to the reality that the page I&amp;#8217;ve been building will shortly be displayed to
millions of users who view Groupon on their mobile or tablet device. It seems like a small project when I&amp;#8217;m sitting there with a few
tiny files make some changes in the HTML and CSS but that page along with the whole touch version will soon be viewed by an enormous
user base &amp;mdash; pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with the above, it&amp;#8217;s also a very exciting time to be there considering Groupon&amp;#8217;s insurmountable amount of media attention lately.
I came at the right time just about when all the action is taking place. My first week we released our partnership with Expedia to provide
travel deals. We also just released our partnership with foursquare today. Although a bit behind some of the other Daily Deal sites (i.e.
LivingSocial and Gilt Groupe), our partnership with them is different because we also include Now! Deals, which allows users to redeem
deals immediately when they check into a location, unlike the other deal sites who do not provide immediate redemption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a final note, the last thing I want to say is how much I&amp;#8217;ve come to appreciate the humor of Groupon. Some of the emails between customer
service and customers are absolutely hilarious as well as the multitude of other humorous jokes or situations we&amp;#8217;ve been in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to the coming weeks there!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Journey</title>
    <link href="http://benjreinhart.github.com/blog/2011/07/27/journey/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-27T22:51:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://benjreinhart.github.com/blog/2011/07/27/journey</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: this post was originally written sometime in April and ported over on July 27th, 2011&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I was fortunate enough to go to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://obtiva.com/&quot;&gt;Obtiva&lt;/a&gt; office for a personal tour by Obtiva’s founder, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ktaylor.name/&quot;&gt;Kevin Taylor&lt;/a&gt;. Kevin is actually one of my professors at DePaul, he teaches a class on entrepreneurism and tech start ups. I was thrilled to go to Obtiva, mostly because it’s a development shop—they develop applications in house with a pretty good size team of seasoned developers—and because some of the people who work there are largely involved and respected in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The office was really nice and comfortable and I quickly met &lt;a href=&quot;http://redsquirrel.com/dave/&quot;&gt;Dave Hoover&lt;/a&gt;, Chief Craftsman at Obtiva and author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Apprenticeship-Patterns-Guidance-Aspiring-Craftsman/dp/0596518382/&quot;&gt;Apprenticeship Patterns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. I have followed Dave on Twitter for a while now and have really begun to respect his involvement in the community. He was very kind and gave me a copy of his book and signed it for me (thank you!). I also met &lt;a href=&quot;http://railsrx.com/&quot;&gt;Noel Rappin&lt;/a&gt;, Senior Consultant at Obtiva and author of &lt;a href=&quot;http://pragprog.com/book/nrtest/rails-test-prescriptions&quot;&gt;Rails Test Prescriptions&lt;/a&gt;. Kevin asked if he could give me a copy of his book as well, but luckily for him I already bought it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the tour, I was shocked when Kevin asked me if I’d like to sit down with the developers in the shop and work with them for as long as I’d like. I was thrilled even though unfortunately I knew I’d be of no help to them. Either way, I sat down for about an hour and observed, taking in what I could. It was cool to experience a respected development shop first hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I left and went to school, really excited to read my new book that Dave gave me. I spent the afternoon working on implementing a data structure (linked list) in C++ for my class. I was happy to finally get my program to work after struggling with it the previous week. I went home and after watching the Red Wings own the Coyotes I began to read Dave’s book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apprenticeship Patterns is a book catered towards beginners wishing to become software craftsman (me). It is meant to help beginners with their journey to becoming a ‘master’ in their craft (although, no one is ever a master). I am only on the second chapter but already the book resonates with me so well. I am one year into my journey and have mostly just figured out my ignorance when it comes to the limitless amount of knowledge it takes to become a craftsman in my field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really feel strongly that this is the right time for me to be reading this book considering it has already had such an impact on me. Much of what has been discussed so far has already been reflected in my (brief) career in one way or another. After feeling accomplished with some tedious C++ homework, this experience at Obtiva, and Dave’s book, I’m feeling more excited and confident than ever to begin my journey into the world of software craftsmanship.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
